<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2022-11-13T03:36:16+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aradhana’s Website</title><subtitle>Aradhana's Website</subtitle><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Scarlet Letter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The-Scarlet-Letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Scarlet Letter" /><published>2022-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The%20Scarlet%20Letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The-Scarlet-Letter/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Author: Written by Nathaniel Hawthorne</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Gothic Romance</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/InPageScarlet.png" alt="The Scarlet Letter" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Set in the Puritan Massachusetts Bay Colony, “The Scarlet Letter” follows the story of Hester Prynne. A woman who is branded with a scarlet A on her chest for the sin of adultery. As a result of her actions, Hester conceives a child named Pearl. With nobody but herself, Hester must now learn how to live in a society openly branded with sin.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>PURPOSE</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Hawthorne’s purpose in writing “The Scarlet Letter” was to portray the message that no matter the class, everybody can commit sin. This is seen with the characters Hester and Dimmesdale. One is a simple woman while the other is a spiritual speaker. The story also shows how people learn to deal with the aftermath of their sins, and how they can grow from them. This is seen in Hester who throughout the story learns more about herself, and in the end accepts the scarlet letter as a part of herself.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>One of the big themes of “The Scarlet Letter” is sin, symbolized by the scarlet letter Hester wears on her chest. As Hester has a child, Pearl, she becomes branded as an adulterer. As such, she is forced to wear a scarlet A on her chest for everyone to see. And as soon as anyone in the town sees that letter, they immediately associate Hester with the sin of adultery. However, this allows Hester the freedom to question the society that she resides in and become more exploratory towards her own identity and grow from it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another main theme of the novel is the nature of evil. Throughout the novel there is the constant question of who the Black Man is, as he is the one who embodies evil. More specifically two characters are questioned to be identified as the Black Man. First is Dimmesdale, who claims to love Pearl, yet refuses to acknowledge her nor Hester in the public eye. Second is Chillingworth, whose purpose is to act revenge on Hester for her sin of adultery. There are also those in the town who claim Pearl to be the child of the Devil due to the circumstances surrounding her birth.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another theme of “The Scarlet Letter” is guilt. This is embodied by the character Dimmesdale. Throughout the novel, Dimmesdale is seen clutching his heart, which causes the aid of Chillingworth’s doctoral expertise. His guilt stems from the sin of being the father of an illegitimate child, Pearl, and his incapability to take responsibility for taking care of her. His guilt only increases as he continues to keep this a secret, which leads to his demise.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A big theme of “The Scarlet Letter” that also plays into today’s time is female independence. Since society had ostracized Hester, she was forced to find a way to provide for herself and her daughter. In addition to that, Hester learned how to be a single mother and was not burdened by society’s image of women (having to be docile and submissive). This plays into today’s time as being a classic piece of literature that symbolizes feminism before its time, and how women are forced to confine to the images of society and suffer the consequences of nonconformity.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>I really enjoyed this book. I first read it in high school, and was not a fan, but I am glad I gave it another chance. After reading it for a second time, I got to see more little details that I did see before. An example is when Hester and Pearl are in the forest meeting Dimmesdale. Pearl sees the silhouette of Dimmesdale and asks Hester if he is the Black Man. I find this ironically funny, because before I did not know that spiritual men wore black attire with a Bible under their arm. This is ironic because it is the same attire of the Black Man, the only difference is the book the Black Man carries is a ledger and not a Bible. The writing was good and easy to follow. This time around I ended up buying the eBook, and it was nice to see the little drawings scattered through it that helped visualize the story better.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this story to those in search of classic literature. And a great example of a romance defined by that time. If looking for additions to your classic literature collection, “The Scarlet Letter” is one to have. There are so many literary themes and symbols throughout this book, it’s worth reading more than once.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author: Written by Nathaniel Hawthorne Genre: Gothic Romance Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY Set in the Puritan Massachusetts Bay Colony, “The Scarlet Letter” follows the story of Hester Prynne. A woman who is branded with a scarlet A on her chest for the sin of adultery. As a result of her actions, Hester conceives a child named Pearl. With nobody but herself, Hester must now learn how to live in a society openly branded with sin. PURPOSE Hawthorne’s purpose in writing “The Scarlet Letter” was to portray the message that no matter the class, everybody can commit sin. This is seen with the characters Hester and Dimmesdale. One is a simple woman while the other is a spiritual speaker. The story also shows how people learn to deal with the aftermath of their sins, and how they can grow from them. This is seen in Hester who throughout the story learns more about herself, and in the end accepts the scarlet letter as a part of herself. THEMES One of the big themes of “The Scarlet Letter” is sin, symbolized by the scarlet letter Hester wears on her chest. As Hester has a child, Pearl, she becomes branded as an adulterer. As such, she is forced to wear a scarlet A on her chest for everyone to see. And as soon as anyone in the town sees that letter, they immediately associate Hester with the sin of adultery. However, this allows Hester the freedom to question the society that she resides in and become more exploratory towards her own identity and grow from it. Another main theme of the novel is the nature of evil. Throughout the novel there is the constant question of who the Black Man is, as he is the one who embodies evil. More specifically two characters are questioned to be identified as the Black Man. First is Dimmesdale, who claims to love Pearl, yet refuses to acknowledge her nor Hester in the public eye. Second is Chillingworth, whose purpose is to act revenge on Hester for her sin of adultery. There are also those in the town who claim Pearl to be the child of the Devil due to the circumstances surrounding her birth. Another theme of “The Scarlet Letter” is guilt. This is embodied by the character Dimmesdale. Throughout the novel, Dimmesdale is seen clutching his heart, which causes the aid of Chillingworth’s doctoral expertise. His guilt stems from the sin of being the father of an illegitimate child, Pearl, and his incapability to take responsibility for taking care of her. His guilt only increases as he continues to keep this a secret, which leads to his demise. A big theme of “The Scarlet Letter” that also plays into today’s time is female independence. Since society had ostracized Hester, she was forced to find a way to provide for herself and her daughter. In addition to that, Hester learned how to be a single mother and was not burdened by society’s image of women (having to be docile and submissive). This plays into today’s time as being a classic piece of literature that symbolizes feminism before its time, and how women are forced to confine to the images of society and suffer the consequences of nonconformity. THOUGHTS I really enjoyed this book. I first read it in high school, and was not a fan, but I am glad I gave it another chance. After reading it for a second time, I got to see more little details that I did see before. An example is when Hester and Pearl are in the forest meeting Dimmesdale. Pearl sees the silhouette of Dimmesdale and asks Hester if he is the Black Man. I find this ironically funny, because before I did not know that spiritual men wore black attire with a Bible under their arm. This is ironic because it is the same attire of the Black Man, the only difference is the book the Black Man carries is a ledger and not a Bible. The writing was good and easy to follow. This time around I ended up buying the eBook, and it was nice to see the little drawings scattered through it that helped visualize the story better. RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this story to those in search of classic literature. And a great example of a romance defined by that time. If looking for additions to your classic literature collection, “The Scarlet Letter” is one to have. There are so many literary themes and symbols throughout this book, it’s worth reading more than once.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rip Van Winkle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip-Van-Winkle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rip Van Winkle" /><published>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip%20Van%20Winkle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip-Van-Winkle/"><![CDATA[<p>Book Title: Rip Van Winkle
<strong><em>Author: Washington Irving</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Fantasy</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/rvw.png" alt="Rip Van Winkle" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>There is a village that resides near the Catskill Mountains in New York. In this village is a man by the name Rip Van Winkle. He is favored by the people in the village for all the help he does for them. Yet Rip Van Winkle can not do a single piece of work for his own land. This causes Rip Van Winkle’s relationship with his wife to become unfavorable. One day Rip Van Winkle decides to take a trek up the mountain. On his walk up the mountain, he meets a group of men around a fire. They kindly offer Rip Van Winkle a drink, which he accepts and perhaps has too many. Rip Van Winkle decides to take a nap on the side of the mountain, but when he wakes up his village is not how he remembers.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>I’m One of the themes of “Rip Van Winkle” is tyranny. Through the story, Rip Van Winkle is plagued by the tyranny of his marriage and day-to-day responsibilities. Rip Van Winkle’s wife is constantly nagging at him for not working on his farm, leading Rip Van Winkle to become a “henpecked” husband. There is also the tyranny of being a citizen under King George III. During the time of the story, Rip Van Winkle would have been subjected to become a soldier in the war, instead Rip Van Winkle falls asleep. This also ties in with the theme of freedom. The end of the story, Rip Van Winkle is free of responsibility, free of his nagging wife, and free of expectation. Another theme is progress and change. This is seen through the progress of time from before and after Rip Van Winkle’s nap. Before Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was under imperial rule. After Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was in the aftermath of the revolutionary war. The village progressed to freedom.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Irving has once again written a small tale of a man whose fate is not what it seems. After reading this story, I was surprised with the ending. I will not say what happens, you can experience that end for yourself. But I will say, it was a nice little wrapped present with a bow. It was evident that the story was showing the acceptance of change and time as one experiences life, and how readily Rip Van Winkle did. The story was well written and easily understandable. I found the character of Rip Van Winkle very interesting, how he was able to help everyone around him yet couldn’t help himself. It seemed though at the end of the story that Rip Van Winkle finally got what he desired, which was nice.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this tale to those who enjoy a short story with a twist. Although it was a slow beginning, it was definitely worth reading til the end. The story was well executed and had a nice flow to it with a plot twist ending that suited Rip Van Winkle. It was a contrast to that of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” in the sense of story. They had completely opposite objectives towards love, and different outcomes. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen for a second reading.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Book Title: Rip Van Winkle Author: Washington Irving Genre: Fantasy Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY There is a village that resides near the Catskill Mountains in New York. In this village is a man by the name Rip Van Winkle. He is favored by the people in the village for all the help he does for them. Yet Rip Van Winkle can not do a single piece of work for his own land. This causes Rip Van Winkle’s relationship with his wife to become unfavorable. One day Rip Van Winkle decides to take a trek up the mountain. On his walk up the mountain, he meets a group of men around a fire. They kindly offer Rip Van Winkle a drink, which he accepts and perhaps has too many. Rip Van Winkle decides to take a nap on the side of the mountain, but when he wakes up his village is not how he remembers. THEMES I’m One of the themes of “Rip Van Winkle” is tyranny. Through the story, Rip Van Winkle is plagued by the tyranny of his marriage and day-to-day responsibilities. Rip Van Winkle’s wife is constantly nagging at him for not working on his farm, leading Rip Van Winkle to become a “henpecked” husband. There is also the tyranny of being a citizen under King George III. During the time of the story, Rip Van Winkle would have been subjected to become a soldier in the war, instead Rip Van Winkle falls asleep. This also ties in with the theme of freedom. The end of the story, Rip Van Winkle is free of responsibility, free of his nagging wife, and free of expectation. Another theme is progress and change. This is seen through the progress of time from before and after Rip Van Winkle’s nap. Before Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was under imperial rule. After Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was in the aftermath of the revolutionary war. The village progressed to freedom. THOUGHTS Irving has once again written a small tale of a man whose fate is not what it seems. After reading this story, I was surprised with the ending. I will not say what happens, you can experience that end for yourself. But I will say, it was a nice little wrapped present with a bow. It was evident that the story was showing the acceptance of change and time as one experiences life, and how readily Rip Van Winkle did. The story was well written and easily understandable. I found the character of Rip Van Winkle very interesting, how he was able to help everyone around him yet couldn’t help himself. It seemed though at the end of the story that Rip Van Winkle finally got what he desired, which was nice. RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this tale to those who enjoy a short story with a twist. Although it was a slow beginning, it was definitely worth reading til the end. The story was well executed and had a nice flow to it with a plot twist ending that suited Rip Van Winkle. It was a contrast to that of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” in the sense of story. They had completely opposite objectives towards love, and different outcomes. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen for a second reading.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>