<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2022-11-14T22:57:45+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aradhana’s Website</title><subtitle>Aradhana's Website</subtitle><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Scarlet Letter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The-Scarlet-Letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Scarlet Letter" /><published>2022-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The%20Scarlet%20Letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/10/The-Scarlet-Letter/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Author: Written by Nathaniel Hawthorne</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Gothic Romance</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/InPageScarlet.png" alt="The Scarlet Letter" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Set in the Puritan Massachusetts Bay Colony, “The Scarlet Letter” follows the story of Hester Prynne. A woman who is branded with a scarlet A on her chest for the sin of adultery. As a result of her actions, Hester conceives a child named Pearl. With nobody but herself, Hester must now learn how to live in a society openly branded with sin.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>PURPOSE</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Hawthorne’s purpose in writing “The Scarlet Letter” was to portray the message that no matter the class, everybody can commit sin. This is seen with the characters Hester and Dimmesdale. One is a simple woman while the other is a spiritual speaker. The story also shows how people learn to deal with the aftermath of their sins, and how they can grow from them. This is seen in Hester who throughout the story learns more about herself, and in the end accepts the scarlet letter as a part of herself.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>One of the big themes of “The Scarlet Letter” is sin, symbolized by the scarlet letter Hester wears on her chest. As Hester has a child, Pearl, she becomes branded as an adulterer. As such, she is forced to wear a scarlet A on her chest for everyone to see. And as soon as anyone in the town sees that letter, they immediately associate Hester with the sin of adultery. However, this allows Hester the freedom to question the society that she resides in and become more exploratory towards her own identity and grow from it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another main theme of the novel is the nature of evil. Throughout the novel there is the constant question of who the Black Man is, as he is the one who embodies evil. More specifically two characters are questioned to be identified as the Black Man. First is Dimmesdale, who claims to love Pearl, yet refuses to acknowledge her nor Hester in the public eye. Second is Chillingworth, whose purpose is to act revenge on Hester for her sin of adultery. There are also those in the town who claim Pearl to be the child of the Devil due to the circumstances surrounding her birth.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another theme of “The Scarlet Letter” is guilt. This is embodied by the character Dimmesdale. Throughout the novel, Dimmesdale is seen clutching his heart, which causes the aid of Chillingworth’s doctoral expertise. His guilt stems from the sin of being the father of an illegitimate child, Pearl, and his incapability to take responsibility for taking care of her. His guilt only increases as he continues to keep this a secret, which leads to his demise.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A big theme of “The Scarlet Letter” that also plays into today’s time is female independence. Since society had ostracized Hester, she was forced to find a way to provide for herself and her daughter. In addition to that, Hester learned how to be a single mother and was not burdened by society’s image of women (having to be docile and submissive). This plays into today’s time as being a classic piece of literature that symbolizes feminism before its time, and how women are forced to confine to the images of society and suffer the consequences of nonconformity.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>I really enjoyed this book. I first read it in high school, and was not a fan, but I am glad I gave it another chance. After reading it for a second time, I got to see more little details that I did see before. An example is when Hester and Pearl are in the forest meeting Dimmesdale. Pearl sees the silhouette of Dimmesdale and asks Hester if he is the Black Man. I find this ironically funny, because before I did not know that spiritual men wore black attire with a Bible under their arm. This is ironic because it is the same attire of the Black Man, the only difference is the book the Black Man carries is a ledger and not a Bible. The writing was good and easy to follow. This time around I ended up buying the eBook, and it was nice to see the little drawings scattered through it that helped visualize the story better.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this story to those in search of classic literature. And a great example of a romance defined by that time. If looking for additions to your classic literature collection, “The Scarlet Letter” is one to have. There are so many literary themes and symbols throughout this book, it’s worth reading more than once.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author: Written by Nathaniel Hawthorne Genre: Gothic Romance Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY Set in the Puritan Massachusetts Bay Colony, “The Scarlet Letter” follows the story of Hester Prynne. A woman who is branded with a scarlet A on her chest for the sin of adultery. As a result of her actions, Hester conceives a child named Pearl. With nobody but herself, Hester must now learn how to live in a society openly branded with sin. PURPOSE Hawthorne’s purpose in writing “The Scarlet Letter” was to portray the message that no matter the class, everybody can commit sin. This is seen with the characters Hester and Dimmesdale. One is a simple woman while the other is a spiritual speaker. The story also shows how people learn to deal with the aftermath of their sins, and how they can grow from them. This is seen in Hester who throughout the story learns more about herself, and in the end accepts the scarlet letter as a part of herself. THEMES One of the big themes of “The Scarlet Letter” is sin, symbolized by the scarlet letter Hester wears on her chest. As Hester has a child, Pearl, she becomes branded as an adulterer. As such, she is forced to wear a scarlet A on her chest for everyone to see. And as soon as anyone in the town sees that letter, they immediately associate Hester with the sin of adultery. However, this allows Hester the freedom to question the society that she resides in and become more exploratory towards her own identity and grow from it. Another main theme of the novel is the nature of evil. Throughout the novel there is the constant question of who the Black Man is, as he is the one who embodies evil. More specifically two characters are questioned to be identified as the Black Man. First is Dimmesdale, who claims to love Pearl, yet refuses to acknowledge her nor Hester in the public eye. Second is Chillingworth, whose purpose is to act revenge on Hester for her sin of adultery. There are also those in the town who claim Pearl to be the child of the Devil due to the circumstances surrounding her birth. Another theme of “The Scarlet Letter” is guilt. This is embodied by the character Dimmesdale. Throughout the novel, Dimmesdale is seen clutching his heart, which causes the aid of Chillingworth’s doctoral expertise. His guilt stems from the sin of being the father of an illegitimate child, Pearl, and his incapability to take responsibility for taking care of her. His guilt only increases as he continues to keep this a secret, which leads to his demise. A big theme of “The Scarlet Letter” that also plays into today’s time is female independence. Since society had ostracized Hester, she was forced to find a way to provide for herself and her daughter. In addition to that, Hester learned how to be a single mother and was not burdened by society’s image of women (having to be docile and submissive). This plays into today’s time as being a classic piece of literature that symbolizes feminism before its time, and how women are forced to confine to the images of society and suffer the consequences of nonconformity. THOUGHTS I really enjoyed this book. I first read it in high school, and was not a fan, but I am glad I gave it another chance. After reading it for a second time, I got to see more little details that I did see before. An example is when Hester and Pearl are in the forest meeting Dimmesdale. Pearl sees the silhouette of Dimmesdale and asks Hester if he is the Black Man. I find this ironically funny, because before I did not know that spiritual men wore black attire with a Bible under their arm. This is ironic because it is the same attire of the Black Man, the only difference is the book the Black Man carries is a ledger and not a Bible. The writing was good and easy to follow. This time around I ended up buying the eBook, and it was nice to see the little drawings scattered through it that helped visualize the story better. RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this story to those in search of classic literature. And a great example of a romance defined by that time. If looking for additions to your classic literature collection, “The Scarlet Letter” is one to have. There are so many literary themes and symbols throughout this book, it’s worth reading more than once.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rip Van Winkle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip-Van-Winkle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rip Van Winkle" /><published>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip%20Van%20Winkle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Rip-Van-Winkle/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Author: Washington Irving</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Fantasy</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/rvw.png" alt="Rip Van Winkle" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>There is a village that resides near the Catskill Mountains in New York. In this village is a man by the name Rip Van Winkle. He is favored by the people in the village for all the help he does for them. Yet Rip Van Winkle can not do a single piece of work for his own land. This causes Rip Van Winkle’s relationship with his wife to become unfavorable. One day Rip Van Winkle decides to take a trek up the mountain. On his walk up the mountain, he meets a group of men around a fire. They kindly offer Rip Van Winkle a drink, which he accepts and perhaps has too many. Rip Van Winkle decides to take a nap on the side of the mountain, but when he wakes up his village is not how he remembers.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>I’m One of the themes of “Rip Van Winkle” is tyranny. Through the story, Rip Van Winkle is plagued by the tyranny of his marriage and day-to-day responsibilities. Rip Van Winkle’s wife is constantly nagging at him for not working on his farm, leading Rip Van Winkle to become a “henpecked” husband. There is also the tyranny of being a citizen under King George III. During the time of the story, Rip Van Winkle would have been subjected to become a soldier in the war, instead Rip Van Winkle falls asleep. This also ties in with the theme of freedom. The end of the story, Rip Van Winkle is free of responsibility, free of his nagging wife, and free of expectation. Another theme is progress and change. This is seen through the progress of time from before and after Rip Van Winkle’s nap. Before Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was under imperial rule. After Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was in the aftermath of the revolutionary war. The village progressed to freedom.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Irving has once again written a small tale of a man whose fate is not what it seems. After reading this story, I was surprised with the ending. I will not say what happens, you can experience that end for yourself. But I will say, it was a nice little wrapped present with a bow. It was evident that the story was showing the acceptance of change and time as one experiences life, and how readily Rip Van Winkle did. The story was well written and easily understandable. I found the character of Rip Van Winkle very interesting, how he was able to help everyone around him yet couldn’t help himself. It seemed though at the end of the story that Rip Van Winkle finally got what he desired, which was nice.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this tale to those who enjoy a short story with a twist. Although it was a slow beginning, it was definitely worth reading til the end. The story was well executed and had a nice flow to it with a plot twist ending that suited Rip Van Winkle. It was a contrast to that of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” in the sense of story. They had completely opposite objectives towards love, and different outcomes. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen for a second reading.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author: Washington Irving Genre: Fantasy Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY There is a village that resides near the Catskill Mountains in New York. In this village is a man by the name Rip Van Winkle. He is favored by the people in the village for all the help he does for them. Yet Rip Van Winkle can not do a single piece of work for his own land. This causes Rip Van Winkle’s relationship with his wife to become unfavorable. One day Rip Van Winkle decides to take a trek up the mountain. On his walk up the mountain, he meets a group of men around a fire. They kindly offer Rip Van Winkle a drink, which he accepts and perhaps has too many. Rip Van Winkle decides to take a nap on the side of the mountain, but when he wakes up his village is not how he remembers. THEMES I’m One of the themes of “Rip Van Winkle” is tyranny. Through the story, Rip Van Winkle is plagued by the tyranny of his marriage and day-to-day responsibilities. Rip Van Winkle’s wife is constantly nagging at him for not working on his farm, leading Rip Van Winkle to become a “henpecked” husband. There is also the tyranny of being a citizen under King George III. During the time of the story, Rip Van Winkle would have been subjected to become a soldier in the war, instead Rip Van Winkle falls asleep. This also ties in with the theme of freedom. The end of the story, Rip Van Winkle is free of responsibility, free of his nagging wife, and free of expectation. Another theme is progress and change. This is seen through the progress of time from before and after Rip Van Winkle’s nap. Before Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was under imperial rule. After Rip Van Winkle’s nap, the village was in the aftermath of the revolutionary war. The village progressed to freedom. THOUGHTS Irving has once again written a small tale of a man whose fate is not what it seems. After reading this story, I was surprised with the ending. I will not say what happens, you can experience that end for yourself. But I will say, it was a nice little wrapped present with a bow. It was evident that the story was showing the acceptance of change and time as one experiences life, and how readily Rip Van Winkle did. The story was well written and easily understandable. I found the character of Rip Van Winkle very interesting, how he was able to help everyone around him yet couldn’t help himself. It seemed though at the end of the story that Rip Van Winkle finally got what he desired, which was nice. RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this tale to those who enjoy a short story with a twist. Although it was a slow beginning, it was definitely worth reading til the end. The story was well executed and had a nice flow to it with a plot twist ending that suited Rip Van Winkle. It was a contrast to that of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” in the sense of story. They had completely opposite objectives towards love, and different outcomes. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen for a second reading.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Legend of Sleepy Hollow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Sleepy-Hollow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Legend of Sleepy Hollow" /><published>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Sleepy%20Hollow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/26/Sleepy-Hollow/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Author: Written by Washington Irving</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Gothic Fiction</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/sleepyhollow.jpg" alt="Sleep Hollow" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>“The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” is a gothic fiction tale of Ichabod Crane and his time in Sleepy Hollow. Sleepy Hollow is a small, quiet town in New York that has its own supernatural mysteries. More specifically the ghost of the Headless Horseman. In this tale, Ichabod Crane tries to win the heart of Ms. Katarina Van Tassel. Though it is not an easy feat, as Katrina had many previous suitors and the most prevalent Mr. Brom Bones. As Ichabod Crane pursues Ms. Katrina, Mr. Brom Bones is there to upend all his attempts and scare Ichabod away. However, Ichabod is not easily swayed by Mr. Brom Bones’ antics. And it isn’t until a party held by Ms. Katrina Van Tassel that tells the fate of Mr. Ichabod Crane.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>One theme of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” is the supernatural. The entire town of Sleepy Hollow was claimed to be haunted by ghosts and spirits. Some townsfolk say the land was bewitched, while others claim that the land was cursed by a Native American chief when the town took over the land. The most prominent ghost is the Spirit of a Hessian soldier who lost his head during the war. Now, the soldier roams the night in search of his missing head. The scary part, in place of his head, is a pumpkin, giving the soldier the nickname of The Headless Horseman.</li>
  <li>Another theme is the greed that follows the two main characters Ichabod Crane and Karina Van Tassel. Ichabod has an eye for that of fortune, which would make sense seeing as though he makes and has very little when living in Sleepy Hollow. It is that search for fortune, that greed, that lead him to pursue the affection of Karina Van Tassel, in hopes of gaining her wealth. Karina Van Tassel herself expressed greed in the form of vanity. Karina is constantly being met with suitors who are fighting for her hand in marriage. She loves the attention all these men are giving, with complete disregard to them as people.</li>
  <li>A theme within this story that is representative of the time of when the story was written is War. Irving wrote “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” after the American Revolution. However, instead of it being a war of territory and land, this war is of the heart. The main plot of the story is the battle for the heart of Katrina Van Tassel. Ichabod Crane and Brom Bones are the two sides at war, and the prize if Katrina Van Tassel.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Upon first reading the title “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow”, I got excited for a gothic ghost story. Upon completion of reading the tale, I was disappointed to say the least. Instead of getting the story of the Headless Horseman that movie and tv shows made a Halloween staple, Irving delivered a story of courtship. Barely mentioned, (if only thrice), the Headless Horsemen does not receive much of any acknowledgements. The tale was more focused on the detailed aspects of the surrounding environment to which Ichabod lived in Sleepy Hollow. It is understandable to set a scene by describing the nature of the background that characters pass the time, but this was more excessive. The scenery was described more so to shine the light on all the resources the characters have, and the atmosphere of the little town called Sleepy Hollow. Aside from the plot, the point of view of the story was at times confusing. Most of the story is written in the limited third person, using pronouns such as she, he, them, it, however there were also points where the perspective would switch to first person, using I and myself. Although underneath the story’s title is the acknowledgement of finding this “among the papers of the Late Diedrich Knickerbocker”, nowhere does the story address that it is one that is being told rather than read.  Aside from that, the story flows easily and is easy to understand for older literature. Irving gives well written, vivid imagery that allows readers to readily visualize being in Sleepy Hollow themselves. Which for being a reader, is one of the most crucial components in a story. </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this story to those with a taste for the gothic genre. The tale was well written to express the supernatural and mystery that resides in Sleepy Hollow. I would have picked this story as a Halloween or October read but would rather pick the video media for more Headless Horsemen focused content. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen as a seasonal reread.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author: Written by Washington Irving Genre: Gothic Fiction Rating: ⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” is a gothic fiction tale of Ichabod Crane and his time in Sleepy Hollow. Sleepy Hollow is a small, quiet town in New York that has its own supernatural mysteries. More specifically the ghost of the Headless Horseman. In this tale, Ichabod Crane tries to win the heart of Ms. Katarina Van Tassel. Though it is not an easy feat, as Katrina had many previous suitors and the most prevalent Mr. Brom Bones. As Ichabod Crane pursues Ms. Katrina, Mr. Brom Bones is there to upend all his attempts and scare Ichabod away. However, Ichabod is not easily swayed by Mr. Brom Bones’ antics. And it isn’t until a party held by Ms. Katrina Van Tassel that tells the fate of Mr. Ichabod Crane. THEMES One theme of “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” is the supernatural. The entire town of Sleepy Hollow was claimed to be haunted by ghosts and spirits. Some townsfolk say the land was bewitched, while others claim that the land was cursed by a Native American chief when the town took over the land. The most prominent ghost is the Spirit of a Hessian soldier who lost his head during the war. Now, the soldier roams the night in search of his missing head. The scary part, in place of his head, is a pumpkin, giving the soldier the nickname of The Headless Horseman. Another theme is the greed that follows the two main characters Ichabod Crane and Karina Van Tassel. Ichabod has an eye for that of fortune, which would make sense seeing as though he makes and has very little when living in Sleepy Hollow. It is that search for fortune, that greed, that lead him to pursue the affection of Karina Van Tassel, in hopes of gaining her wealth. Karina Van Tassel herself expressed greed in the form of vanity. Karina is constantly being met with suitors who are fighting for her hand in marriage. She loves the attention all these men are giving, with complete disregard to them as people. A theme within this story that is representative of the time of when the story was written is War. Irving wrote “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” after the American Revolution. However, instead of it being a war of territory and land, this war is of the heart. The main plot of the story is the battle for the heart of Katrina Van Tassel. Ichabod Crane and Brom Bones are the two sides at war, and the prize if Katrina Van Tassel. THOUGHTS Upon first reading the title “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow”, I got excited for a gothic ghost story. Upon completion of reading the tale, I was disappointed to say the least. Instead of getting the story of the Headless Horseman that movie and tv shows made a Halloween staple, Irving delivered a story of courtship. Barely mentioned, (if only thrice), the Headless Horsemen does not receive much of any acknowledgements. The tale was more focused on the detailed aspects of the surrounding environment to which Ichabod lived in Sleepy Hollow. It is understandable to set a scene by describing the nature of the background that characters pass the time, but this was more excessive. The scenery was described more so to shine the light on all the resources the characters have, and the atmosphere of the little town called Sleepy Hollow. Aside from the plot, the point of view of the story was at times confusing. Most of the story is written in the limited third person, using pronouns such as she, he, them, it, however there were also points where the perspective would switch to first person, using I and myself. Although underneath the story’s title is the acknowledgement of finding this “among the papers of the Late Diedrich Knickerbocker”, nowhere does the story address that it is one that is being told rather than read. Aside from that, the story flows easily and is easy to understand for older literature. Irving gives well written, vivid imagery that allows readers to readily visualize being in Sleepy Hollow themselves. Which for being a reader, is one of the most crucial components in a story.  RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this story to those with a taste for the gothic genre. The tale was well written to express the supernatural and mystery that resides in Sleepy Hollow. I would have picked this story as a Halloween or October read but would rather pick the video media for more Headless Horsemen focused content. I do suggest reading it for the first time, however it will not be chosen as a seasonal reread.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Iroquois Creation Story</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/26/The-Iroquois-Creation-Story/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Iroquois Creation Story" /><published>2022-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/26/The%20Iroquois%20Creation%20Story</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/26/The-Iroquois-Creation-Story/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Author: Written by David Cusick and Translated by Gabriel Sagard</em></strong>
<strong><em>Genre: Native American Oral Literature</em></strong>
<strong><em>Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐</em></strong></p>

<figure class="figure  figure--center">
  <img class="image" src="/assets/ak/iroq.jpeg" alt="Iroquois Creation" width="" height="" />
  
</figure>

<p><strong>SUMMARY</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>“The Iroquois Creation Story” is a Native American Oral story of the establishment of the Iroquois world. The Iroquois consists of the Mohawk, Seneca, Onondaga and Cayuga Native American nations. The story begins with a Sky Woman who is pregnant (without sexual activity) with twins that falls to the Lower World. After giving birth, the Sky Woman dies leaving behind Enigorio (the Good Mind) and Enigonhahetga (the Bad Mind). While living in the Lower World, the Good Mind thinks that the world could be better served with more than the simple darkness that they currently reside in. The Bad Mind however, thinks the Lower World doesn’t need to be changed. Using their mother’s corpse, the Good Mind starts crafting the world — the sun, the soon, the stars, animals and eventually real people. All the while, the Bad Mind tries, yet fails, to upend his brother’s creation of the world. The Bad Mind then challenges the Good Mind to determine who will ultimately become watcher of the universe.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>PURPOSE</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>The author achieves their purpose in illustrating the Iroquois people’s perception of how they came into this world. And this is only one example of the many stories of creation that span across a multitude of religions. For example, the Bible in Christianity, Hindus have the Vedic text, and Muslims have the Quran. “The Iroquois Creation Story” actually holds parallels to the creation of the world in the Bible. In the Bible there is the virgin Mary who gives birth to Jesus. In the Iroquois Story, there is the Sky Woman, who gives birth to the Good and Evil Minds. Similar to the Bible, there is a creator of life or God, who is viewed as good and a Devil ,who is viewed as bad.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THEMES</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>The main theme of this story is the juxtaposition of the Good Mind versus the Evil Mind. The entire story tells of how the Good Mind tries to better the Lower World by creating the sun, moon, stars, and people. In contrast, the Evil Mind believes the Lower World should remain how it is and fails to stop his brother’s creation of the world. Another important theme is the creation of nature, humans and animals. The vivid description of how the earth and humans and animals were created are testaments to the Native Americans’s connection with nature.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>THOUGHTS</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>The story gives the Native’s own perspective on the creation of life, and in adding the Native’s respect to nature, it gives the story a more cultural aspect. The relationship between the Good Mind and Evil Mind makes one question their own personal standing in the world, as well as those they encounter everyday. It brings the question of what an impact a single action or even a single thought can have on those one cares about. It also brings to thought what choices one makes for themselves and whether or not they are in fact “good or bad” for them.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RECOMMENDATION</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>I would recommend this to those who are passionate about the beginnings of the world and to those that are pursuing knowledge on the cultures of the world. The story was well executed and very descriptive in the aspects of death and creation. Personally I would not have picked it up if it were not for it being a topic of study.  It is always an intriguing thought to discover how people began, yet it is in the eye of the beholder on what they choose to believe in.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author: Written by David Cusick and Translated by Gabriel Sagard Genre: Native American Oral Literature Rating: ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ SUMMARY “The Iroquois Creation Story” is a Native American Oral story of the establishment of the Iroquois world. The Iroquois consists of the Mohawk, Seneca, Onondaga and Cayuga Native American nations. The story begins with a Sky Woman who is pregnant (without sexual activity) with twins that falls to the Lower World. After giving birth, the Sky Woman dies leaving behind Enigorio (the Good Mind) and Enigonhahetga (the Bad Mind). While living in the Lower World, the Good Mind thinks that the world could be better served with more than the simple darkness that they currently reside in. The Bad Mind however, thinks the Lower World doesn’t need to be changed. Using their mother’s corpse, the Good Mind starts crafting the world — the sun, the soon, the stars, animals and eventually real people. All the while, the Bad Mind tries, yet fails, to upend his brother’s creation of the world. The Bad Mind then challenges the Good Mind to determine who will ultimately become watcher of the universe. PURPOSE The author achieves their purpose in illustrating the Iroquois people’s perception of how they came into this world. And this is only one example of the many stories of creation that span across a multitude of religions. For example, the Bible in Christianity, Hindus have the Vedic text, and Muslims have the Quran. “The Iroquois Creation Story” actually holds parallels to the creation of the world in the Bible. In the Bible there is the virgin Mary who gives birth to Jesus. In the Iroquois Story, there is the Sky Woman, who gives birth to the Good and Evil Minds. Similar to the Bible, there is a creator of life or God, who is viewed as good and a Devil ,who is viewed as bad. THEMES The main theme of this story is the juxtaposition of the Good Mind versus the Evil Mind. The entire story tells of how the Good Mind tries to better the Lower World by creating the sun, moon, stars, and people. In contrast, the Evil Mind believes the Lower World should remain how it is and fails to stop his brother’s creation of the world. Another important theme is the creation of nature, humans and animals. The vivid description of how the earth and humans and animals were created are testaments to the Native Americans’s connection with nature. THOUGHTS The story gives the Native’s own perspective on the creation of life, and in adding the Native’s respect to nature, it gives the story a more cultural aspect. The relationship between the Good Mind and Evil Mind makes one question their own personal standing in the world, as well as those they encounter everyday. It brings the question of what an impact a single action or even a single thought can have on those one cares about. It also brings to thought what choices one makes for themselves and whether or not they are in fact “good or bad” for them. RECOMMENDATION I would recommend this to those who are passionate about the beginnings of the world and to those that are pursuing knowledge on the cultures of the world. The story was well executed and very descriptive in the aspects of death and creation. Personally I would not have picked it up if it were not for it being a topic of study. It is always an intriguing thought to discover how people began, yet it is in the eye of the beholder on what they choose to believe in.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>